[
  {
    "content": "Ollie was pleased to find his memory so exact; and he afterwards took occasion to ask her, when unattended to by any of the rest, whether all her sisters were at Longbourn.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        162,
        171,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Alices collected behaviour, however, soon quieted his emotion; and as Miss Bingley, vexed and disappointed, dared not approach nearer to Wickham, Georgiana also recovered in time, though not enough to be able to speak any more.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        70,
        82,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        137,
        144,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        146,
        155,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "And, above all, keep Mr. James from fighting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        25,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "How very ill Miss Eliza Mattie looks this morning, Mr. Darcy, she cried;",
    "entities": [
      [
        18,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        37,
        49,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        55,
        60,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Ollie obeyed, and running into her own room for her parasol, attended her noble guest downstairs.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Pearl made no answer, and took her place in the set, amazed at the dignity to which she was arrived in being allowed to stand opposite to Mr. Darcy, and reading in her neighbours looks, their equal amazement in beholding it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        142,
        147,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "His father, Miss Alexander, the late Mr. Darcy, was one of the best men that ever breathed, and the truest friend I ever had; and I can never be in company with this Mr. Darcy without being grieved to the soul by a thousand tender recollections.",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        26,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        41,
        46,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        170,
        175,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        215,
        223,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "His acquaintance with Adam was very trifling.",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        26,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Janice, who fancied she had gained a complete victory over him, continued her triumph.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "cried Leroy, I am excessively diverted.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Kevin had not before believed him quite equal to such assurance; but she sat down, resolving within herself to draw no limits in future to the impudence of an impudent man.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Do not imagine, Miss Lucy, that your ambition will ever be gratified.",
    "entities": [
      [
        21,
        25,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "cried Sandra.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Her mothers ungraciousness, made the sense of what they owed him more painful to Philips mind; and she would, at times, have given anything to be privileged to tell him that his kindness was neither unknown nor unfelt by the whole of the family.",
    "entities": [
      [
        81,
        88,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Andrea, all amazement, though flattered by having a guest of such high importance, received her with the utmost politeness.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Then you would drink a great deal more than you ought, said Mrs. Irene; and if I were to see you at it, I should take away your bottle directly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        65,
        70,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The Longbourn party were the last of all the company to depart, and, by a manoeuvre of Mrs. Violet, had to wait for their carriage a quarter of an hour after everybody else was gone, which gave them time to see how heartily they were wished away by some of the family.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        19,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        92,
        98,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        131,
        140,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "cried Johnny, brightening up for a moment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As for my fair cousins, though my absence may not be long enough to render it necessary, I shall now take the liberty of wishing them health and happiness, not excepting my cousin Vincent.",
    "entities": [
      [
        180,
        187,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "At length, however, his civility was so far awakened as to inquire of Emmett after the health of her family.",
    "entities": [
      [
        70,
        76,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "A deeper shade of hauteur overspread his features, but he said not a word, and Viola, though blaming herself for her own weakness, could not go on.",
    "entities": [
      [
        79,
        84,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I remain, dear sir, with respectful compliments to your lady and daughters, your well-wisher and friend, William Collins At four oclock, therefore, we may expect this peace-making gentleman, said Mr. Charles, as he folded up the letter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        105,
        120,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        124,
        128,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        200,
        207,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He bore with philosophy the conviction that Minnie must now become acquainted with whatever of his ingratitude and falsehood had before been unknown to her; and in spite of every thing, was not wholly without hope that Linda might yet be prevailed on to make his fortune.",
    "entities": [
      [
        44,
        50,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        219,
        224,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Ashley was quite disconcerted.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "said Mrs. Mary more than once, as if the credit of making it rain were all her own.",
    "entities": [
      [
        10,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "To the little town of Lambton, the scene of Mrs. Stephanie former residence, and where she had lately learned some acquaintance still remained, they bent their steps, after having seen all the principal wonders of the country; and within five miles of Lambton, Henrietta found from her aunt that Pemberley was situated.",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        29,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        49,
        58,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        238,
        248,
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        252,
        259,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        261,
        270,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        296,
        305,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Vivian coloured, and said: A little.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Within a short walk of Longbourn lived a family with whom the Tylers were particularly intimate.",
    "entities": [
      [
        23,
        32,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        62,
        68,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The darling wish of his sisters was then gratified; he bought an estate in a neighbouring county to Derbyshire, and Laura and Howard, in addition to every other source of happiness, were within thirty miles of each other.",
    "entities": [
      [
        116,
        121,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        126,
        132,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        194,
        206,
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The eldest of them, a sensible, intelligent young woman, about twenty-seven, was Archies intimate friend.",
    "entities": [
      [
        57,
        75,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        81,
        88,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "On his approaching them soon afterwards, though without seeming to have any intention of speaking, Miss Lucas defied her friend to mention such a subject to him; which immediately provoking Ollie to do it, she turned to him and said: Did you not think, Mr. Darcy, that I expressed myself uncommonly well just now, when I was teasing Colonel Forster to give us a ball at Meryton?",
    "entities": [
      [
        104,
        109,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        190,
        195,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        257,
        262,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        341,
        348,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        370,
        377,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He is certainly a good brother, said Jack, as she walked towards one of the windows.",
    "entities": [
      [
        37,
        41,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        65,
        68,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "But the morrow passed off much better than she expected; for Mrs. Chester luckily stood in such awe of her intended son-in-law that she ventured not to speak to him, unless it was in her power to offer him any attention, or mark her deference for his opinion.",
    "entities": [
      [
        8,
        14,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        66,
        73,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "My fingers, said Roger, do not move over this instrument in the masterly manner which I see so many womens do.",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        22,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Before any answer could arrive from Mr. Collins, or any congratulations to Sam from his wife, the Longbourn family heard that the Collinses were come themselves to Lucas Lodge.",
    "entities": [
      [
        40,
        47,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        75,
        78,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        98,
        107,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        130,
        139,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        164,
        169,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Ora recollected herself soon, and putting the letter away, tried to join with her usual cheerfulness in the general conversation; but Martin felt an anxiety on the subject which drew off her attention even from Wickham; and no sooner had he and his companion taken leave, than a glance from Ora invited her to follow her up stairs.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        3,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        134,
        140,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        211,
        218,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        291,
        294,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "More than once did Julia, in her ramble within the park, unexpectedly meet Mr. Darcy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        19,
        24,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        79,
        84,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Wickhams affection for Lydia was just what Ruth had expected to find it; not equal to Lydias for him.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        23,
        28,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        43,
        47,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        86,
        92,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "46 Earnest had been a good deal disappointed in not finding a letter from Evelyn on their first arrival at Lambton; and this disappointment had been renewed on each of the mornings that had now been spent there; but on the third her repining was over, and her sister justified, by the receipt of two letters from her at once, on one of which was marked that it had been missent elsewhere.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        2,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        3,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        74,
        80,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        90,
        95,
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        107,
        114,
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        223,
        228,
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        296,
        299,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        329,
        332,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Collins welcomed her friend with the liveliest pleasure, and Patrick was more and more satisfied with coming when she found herself so affectionately received.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        66,
        73,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It was not till the afternoon, when he had joined them at tea, that Jeffrey ventured to introduce the subject; and then, on her briefly expressing her sorrow for what he must have endured, he replied, Say nothing of that.",
    "entities": [
      [
        16,
        29,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        68,
        75,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In a few days Mr. Bingley returned Mr. Hildas visit, and sat about ten minutes with him in his library.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        13,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        18,
        25,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        39,
        45,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        61,
        78,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Emmett, still more affected, was earnest and solemn in her reply; and at length, by repeated assurances that Mr. Darcy was really the object of her choice, by explaining the gradual change which her estimation of him had undergone, relating her absolute certainty that his affection was not the work of a day, but had stood the test of many months suspense, and enumerating with energy all his good qualities, she did conquer her fathers incredulity, and reconcile him to the match.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        113,
        118,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        303,
        308,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        336,
        347,
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Bobby looked well, and Adam had little opportunity of studying her spirits, amidst the various engagements which the kindness of her aunt had reserved for them.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        23,
        27,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He scarcely needed an invitation to stay supper; and before he went away, an engagement was formed, chiefly through his own and Mrs. Lindas means, for his coming next morning to shoot with her husband.",
    "entities": [
      [
        133,
        139,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        162,
        174,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "To the rest of the family they paid little attention; avoiding Mrs. Beverly as much as possible, saying not much to Mae, and nothing at all to the others.",
    "entities": [
      [
        68,
        75,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        116,
        119,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Loretta received her congratulations amongst the rest, and then, sick of this folly, took refuge in her own room, that she might think with freedom.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Bens misery increased, at such unnecessary, such officious attention!",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Reynolds respect for Isabella seemed to increase on this intimation of her knowing her master.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        13,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        26,
        34,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Rose was really in a most pitiable state.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "On such encouragement to ask, Ray was forced to put it out of her power, by running away.",
    "entities": [
      [
        30,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Roy listened, wondered, doubted, and was impatient for more.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        3,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Till Michael entered the drawing-room at Netherfield, and looked in vain for Mr. Jeffrey among the cluster of red coats there assembled, a doubt of his being present had never occurred to her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        41,
        52,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        81,
        88,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He had certainly formed such a plan, and without meaning that it should affect his endeavour to separate him from Miss Judith, it is probable that it might add something to his lively concern for the welfare of his friend.",
    "entities": [
      [
        119,
        125,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "No sooner did he appear than Kathleen wisely resolved to be perfectly easy and unembarrassed; a resolution the more necessary to be made, but perhaps not the more easily kept, because she saw that the suspicions of the whole party were awakened against them, and that there was scarcely an eye which did not watch his behaviour when he first came into the room.",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        336,
        341,
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As for Adeline, her thoughts were at Pemberley this evening more than the last; and the evening, though as it passed it seemed long, was not long enough to determine her feelings towards one in that mansion; and she lay awake two whole hours endeavouring to make them out.",
    "entities": [
      [
        7,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        37,
        46,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        47,
        59,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        84,
        95,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        187,
        190,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        226,
        241,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In Jacobs presence she dared not mention Russells name; but Alta instantly comprehended that he was uppermost in her thoughts; and the various recollections connected with him gave her a moments distress; but exerting herself vigorously to repel the ill-natured attack, she presently answered the question in a tolerably detached tone.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        41,
        49,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        60,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Deborahs delicate sense of honour would not allow her to speak to Harvey privately of what Lydia had let fall; Harvey was glad of it;till",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        66,
        72,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        91,
        96,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        111,
        117,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Even Natalie began to fearnot that Bingley was indifferentbut that his sisters would be successful in keeping him away.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        35,
        42,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Really, Mr. Collins, cried Anna with some warmth, you puzzle me exceedingly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        27,
        31,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Virgie could certainly spare you for another fortnight.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I am astonished, my dear, said Mrs. Frieda, that you should be so ready to think your own children silly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        36,
        42,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "They did not see the gentlemen again till Tuesday; and Mrs. Jack, in the meanwhile, was giving way to all the happy schemes, which the good humour and common politeness of Bingley, in half an hours visit, had revived.",
    "entities": [
      [
        42,
        49,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        60,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        172,
        179,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        184,
        197,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "His guilt and his descent appear by your account to be the same, said Nicholas angrily; for I have heard you accuse him of nothing worse than of being the son of Mr. Melvin steward, and of that, I can assure you, he informed me himself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        70,
        78,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        166,
        172,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The sisters, on hearing this, repeated three or four times how much they were grieved, how shocking it was to have a bad cold, and how excessively they disliked being ill themselves; and then thought no more of the matter: and their indifference towards Maria when not immediately before them restored Rufus to the enjoyment of all her former dislike.",
    "entities": [
      [
        39,
        44,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        48,
        52,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        254,
        259,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        302,
        307,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Every park has its beauty and its prospects; and Nancy saw much to be pleased with, though she could not be in such raptures as Mr. Collins expected the scene to inspire, and was but slightly affected by his enumeration of the windows in front of the house, and his relation of what the glazing altogether had originally cost Sir Lewis de Bourgh.",
    "entities": [
      [
        49,
        54,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        132,
        139,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        330,
        345,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "She was perfectly sensible that he never had; but she wished to see whether he would betray any consciousness of what had passed between the Bingleys and Amelia, and she thought he looked a little confused as he answered that he had never been so fortunate as to meet Miss Juan.",
    "entities": [
      [
        141,
        149,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        154,
        160,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        273,
        277,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "cried Mildred.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        13,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You began the evening well, Charlotte, said Mrs. Lisa with civil self-command to Miss Betty.",
    "entities": [
      [
        14,
        21,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        28,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        49,
        53,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        86,
        91,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When the clock struck three, Joan felt that she must go, and very unwillingly said so.",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        27,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        29,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Bessie soon heard from her friend; and their correspondence was as regular and frequent as it had ever been; that it should be equally unreserved was impossible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "My dear Mr. Fred, replied his wife, how can you be so tiresome!",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "True, said Mr. Bonnie, but it is a comfort to think that whatever of that kind may befall you, you have an affectionate mother who will make the most of it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "A short pause followed this speech, and Mrs. Hurst began again: I have an excessive regard for Miss Dennis Albert, she is really a very sweet girl, and I wish with all my heart she were well settled.",
    "entities": [
      [
        45,
        50,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        100,
        113,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It was a fortnight since Mrs. Jeanette had been downstairs; but on this happy day she again took her seat at the head of her table, and in spirits oppressively high.",
    "entities": [
      [
        30,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Oh, no! said Ralph.",
    "entities": [
      [
        13,
        18,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "This is the consequence, you see, Madam, of marrying a daughter, said Isabella.",
    "entities": [
      [
        70,
        78,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Raymond, to whom Raymond very soon communicated the chief of all this, heard it in silent indignation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        17,
        24,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Marvin dared not lift up her eyes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Miriam hoped she had silenced him; but he soon afterwards said: I was surprised to see Edgar in town last month.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        87,
        92,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        101,
        111,
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "That would be a good scheme, said Walter, if you were sure that they would not offer to send her home.",
    "entities": [
      [
        34,
        40,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Linda could not give her consent or speak her approbation in terms warm enough to satisfy her feelings, though she talked to Georgia of nothing else for half an hour; and when Mr. Homer joined them at supper, his voice and manner plainly showed how really happy he was.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        130,
        137,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        158,
        170,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        185,
        190,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lizzie, feeling really anxious, was determined to go to her, though the carriage was not to be had; and as she was no horsewoman, walking was her only alternative.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He was received by Mrs. Ruby with a degree of civility which made her two daughters ashamed, especially when contrasted with the cold and ceremonious politeness of her curtsey and address to his friend.",
    "entities": [
      [
        24,
        28,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        70,
        73,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The idea of Mr. Orville, with all his solemn composure, being run away with by his feelings, made Harry so near laughing, that she could not use the short pause he allowed in any attempt to stop him further, and he continued:",
    "entities": [
      [
        16,
        23,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        98,
        103,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In this manner Lady Catherine talked on, till they were at the door of the carriage, when, turning hastily round, she added, I take no leave of you, Miss Teresa.",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        29,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        154,
        160,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Maria took up a book; Miss Barbara did the same; and Mrs. Susan, principally occupied in playing with her bracelets and rings, joined now and then in her brothers conversation with Miss Francis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        22,
        34,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        58,
        63,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        186,
        193,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Olga again, and more seriously assured her of its truth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Henrietta longed to observe that Mr. Matthew had been a most delightful friend; so easily guided that his worth was invaluable; but she checked herself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        37,
        44,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": ", I beg you will come here, and shoot as many as you please on Mr. Davids manor.",
    "entities": [
      [
        67,
        73,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Ann blushed and blushed again with shame and vexation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        3,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Nellie smiled.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "CLinton of course returned with him to dinner; and in the evening Mrs. Bettys invention was again at work to get every body away from him and her daughter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        58,
        65,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        71,
        77,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When the tea-things were removed, and the card-tables placed, the ladies all rose, and Bernice was then hoping to be soon joined by him, when all her views were overthrown by seeing him fall a victim to her mothers rapacity for whist players, and in a few moments after seated with the rest of the party.",
    "entities": [
      [
        87,
        94,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Otis tried to be diverted by them; but all sense of pleasure was lost in shame.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mr. Anns emotions were much more tranquil on the occasion, and such as he did experience he pronounced to be of a most agreeable sort; for it gratified him, he said, to discover that Geraldine Lucas, whom he had been used to think tolerably sensible, was as foolish as his wife, and more foolish than his daughter!",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        183,
        198,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "At five oclock the two ladies retired to dress, and at half-past six Steven was summoned to dinner.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        7,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        19,
        22,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        55,
        68,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        69,
        75,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The whist party soon afterwards breaking up, the players gathered round the other table and Mr. Collins took his station between his cousin Roger and Mrs. Isabelle.",
    "entities": [
      [
        96,
        103,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        140,
        145,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        155,
        163,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Their arrival was dreaded by the elder Miss Raymonds, and Henry more especially, who gave Allie the feelings which would have attended herself, had she been the culprit, and was wretched in the thought of what her sister must endure.",
    "entities": [
      [
        44,
        52,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        58,
        63,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        90,
        95,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "With no expectation of pleasure, but with the strongest curiosity, Cheryl opened the letter, and, to her still increasing wonder, perceived an envelope containing two sheets of letter-paper, written quite through, in a very close hand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        67,
        73,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        163,
        166,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "They were soon gone again, rising from their seats with an activity which took their brother by surprise, and hurrying off as if eager to escape from Mrs. Pauls civilities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        155,
        160,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mary and Kitty were both with Mrs. Christine: one communication would, therefore, do for all.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        9,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        35,
        44,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        46,
        49,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I thought Miss Julia looked remarkably well when she came into the room this morning.",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        20,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        72,
        84,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Marion could hardly comprehend it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Amanda assured her that they never sat there after dinner, and then added: May I take the liberty of asking your ladyship whether you left Mr. and Mrs. Adeline well.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        157,
        164,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Paul, equally next to Juan in birth and beauty, succeeded her of course.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        22,
        26,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Sophia honoured him for such feelings, and thought him handsomer than ever as he expressed them.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lillie added privately, And how much I shall have to conceal!",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The gentlemen arrived early; and, before Mrs. Freda had time to tell him of their having seen his aunt, of which her daughter sat in momentary dread, Clayton, who wanted to be alone with Sarah, proposed their all walking out.",
    "entities": [
      [
        46,
        51,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        150,
        157,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        187,
        192,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "exclaimed Charley, you are too good.",
    "entities": [
      [
        10,
        17,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When they repaired to the dining-room, Rachel eagerly watched to see whether Clayton would take the place, which, in all their former parties, had belonged to him, by her sister.",
    "entities": [
      [
        39,
        45,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        77,
        84,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "35 Lloyd awoke the next morning to the same thoughts and meditations which had at length closed her eyes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        2,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        3,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        15,
        31,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "to Miss Lydia Freda, without there being a syllable said of her father, or the place where she lived, or anything.",
    "entities": [
      [
        8,
        13,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        14,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "But Stanley, who had not the least inclination to remain with them, laughingly answered: No, no; stay where you are.",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Tyler was privileged to whisper it to Mrs. Phillips, and she ventured, without any permission, to do the same by all her neighbours in Meryton.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        48,
        56,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        140,
        147,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Yes, Miss Clayton, you will have the honour of seeing Lady Catherine de Bourgh on the ensuing Sunday at church, and I need not say you will be delighted with her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        10,
        17,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        54,
        78,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        94,
        100,
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Jake could not but be pleased, could not but triumph.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When breakfast was over they were joined by the sisters; and Mildred began to like them herself, when she saw how much affection and solicitude they showed for Viola.",
    "entities": [
      [
        61,
        68,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        160,
        165,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Louis replied very concisely that she was.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As they drove to Mr. Nathaniel door, Bert was at a drawing-room window watching their arrival; when they entered the passage she was there to welcome them, and Della, looking earnestly in her face, was pleased to see it healthful and lovely as ever.",
    "entities": [
      [
        21,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        37,
        41,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        160,
        165,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Vivian excused herself as well as she could; said that she had liked him better when they had met in Kent than before, and that she had never seen him so pleasant as this morning.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        101,
        105,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The happiness anticipated by Catherine and Lydia depended less on any single event, or any particular person, for though they each, like Jose, meant to dance half the evening with Mr. Abraham, he was by no means the only partner who could satisfy them, and a ball was, at any rate, a ball.",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        43,
        48,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        137,
        141,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        158,
        174,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        184,
        191,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I have been thinking it over again, Charles, said her uncle, as they drove from the town; and really, upon serious consideration, I am much more inclined than I was to judge as your eldest sister does on the matter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        36,
        43,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Bingley was the principal spokesman, and Miss Margaret the principal object.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        46,
        54,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Her resolution was for a short time involuntarily kept by the approach of her sister, who joined her with a cheerful look, which showed her better satisfied with their visitors, than Cheryl.",
    "entities": [
      [
        183,
        189,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "After playing some Italian songs, Miss Bingley varied the charm by a lively Scotch air; and soon afterwards Mr. Darcy, drawing near Dorothy, said to her:",
    "entities": [
      [
        19,
        26,
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        39,
        46,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        76,
        82,
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        112,
        117,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        132,
        139,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Here, Sarah, come to Miss Maggie this moment, and help her on with her gown.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        26,
        32,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Marvin immediately began playing again.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It was rather small, but well built and convenient; and everything was fitted up and arranged with a neatness and consistency of which Sara gave Charlotte all the credit.",
    "entities": [
      [
        135,
        139,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        145,
        154,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The occurrences of the day were too full of interest to leave Megan much attention for any of these new friends; and she could do nothing but think, and think with wonder, of Mr. Darcys civility, and, above all, of his wishing her to be acquainted with his sister.",
    "entities": [
      [
        19,
        26,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        62,
        67,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        179,
        185,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mr. Jerrys expectations were fully answered.",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "An excellent consolation in its way, said Linda, but it will not do for us.",
    "entities": [
      [
        42,
        47,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Goldie made no answer, and walked on, her heart swelling with indignation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lady Catherine observed, after dinner, that Miss Melvin seemed out of spirits, and immediately accounting for it by herself, by supposing that she did not like to go home again so soon, she added:",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        49,
        55,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "They found Mr. Clara still up.",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        20,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "John listened with delight to the happy, though modest hopes which Lula entertained of Mr. Marshall regard, and said all in her power to heighten her confidence in it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        67,
        71,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        91,
        99,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "They all exclaimed against such terrific ideas; and Mr. Franklin, after general assurances of his affection for her and all her family, told her that he meant to be in London the very next day, and would assist Mr. Winifred in every endeavour for recovering Lydia.",
    "entities": [
      [
        56,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        168,
        174,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        184,
        192,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        215,
        223,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        258,
        263,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The pause was to Anns feelings dreadful.",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "thought Bonnie.",
    "entities": [
      [
        8,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Though Darcy could never receive him at Pemberley, yet, for Edwards sake, he assisted him further in his profession.",
    "entities": [
      [
        7,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        40,
        49,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        60,
        67,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "repeated Mr. Charlotte.",
    "entities": [
      [
        13,
        22,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As he spoke there was a sort of smile which William fancied she understood; he must be supposing her to be thinking of Bradley and Netherfield, and she blushed as she answered: I do not mean to say that a woman may not be settled too near her family.",
    "entities": [
      [
        44,
        51,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        119,
        126,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        131,
        142,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Gary would not oppose such an injunctionand",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I never can be thankful, Mr. Rachel, for anything about the entail.",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        35,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In a doleful voice Mrs. Joe began the projected conversation: Oh!",
    "entities": [
      [
        24,
        27,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Patrick was prevented replying by the entrance of the footman with a note for Miss Patrick; it came from Netherfield, and the servant waited for an answer.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        88,
        95,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        110,
        121,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "By Jesses instructions, she began to comprehend that a woman may take liberties with her husband which a brother will not always allow in a sister more than ten years younger than himself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        147,
        156,
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Then turning to Mr. Joshua, he offered himself as his antagonist at backgammon.",
    "entities": [
      [
        20,
        26,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "This was enough to prove that her approbation need not be doubted: and Fred, rejoicing that such an effusion was heard only by herself, soon went away.",
    "entities": [
      [
        71,
        75,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Andrew silently attended her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Perhaps preparing for his marriage with Miss de Bourgh, said Olga.",
    "entities": [
      [
        40,
        54,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        61,
        65,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Miss Hannah, I insist on being satisfied.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "An unhappy alternative is before you, Sidney.",
    "entities": [
      [
        38,
        44,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He was as much awake to the novelty of attention in that quarter as Walter herself could be, and unconsciously closed his book.",
    "entities": [
      [
        52,
        64,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        68,
        74,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "And of your infliction, cried Danielle with energy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        30,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Judy could have no reserves from Philip, where confidence would give pleasure; and instantly embracing her, acknowledged, with the liveliest emotion, that she was the happiest creature in the world.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        33,
        39,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mr. Gardiner declared his willingness, and Norman was applied to for her approbation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        43,
        49,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As Mrs. Gardiner began to wish to be at home, it was settled that she and the children should go to London, at the same time that Mr. Cecil came from it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        8,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        100,
        106,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        134,
        139,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The rapture of Lydia on this occasion, her adoration of Mrs. Forster, the delight of Mrs. Leon, and the mortification of Kitty, are scarcely to be described.",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        20,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        61,
        68,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        90,
        94,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        121,
        126,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "From that moment I observed my friends behaviour attentively; and I could then perceive that his partiality for Miss Paul was beyond what I had ever witnessed in him.",
    "entities": [
      [
        117,
        121,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Bradley made no objection; the door was then allowed to be shut, and the carriage drove off.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Betty, cried Virgil, was there a servant belonging to it who did not know the whole story before the end of the day?",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        13,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        97,
        115,
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I am by no means of the opinion, I assure you, said he, that a ball of this kind, given by a young man of character, to respectable people, can have any evil tendency; and I am so far from objecting to dancing myself, that I shall hope to be honoured with the hands of all my fair cousins in the course of the evening; and I take this opportunity of soliciting yours, Miss Gordon, for the two first dances especially, a preference which I trust my cousin Oliver will attribute to the right cause, and not to any disrespect for her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        306,
        317,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        373,
        379,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        389,
        392,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        393,
        398,
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        455,
        461,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "cried Effie, when she had finished.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "During dinner, Mr. Hugh scarcely spoke at all; but when the servants were withdrawn, he thought it time to have some conversation with his guest, and therefore started a subject in which he expected him to shine, by observing that he seemed very fortunate in his patroness.",
    "entities": [
      [
        19,
        23,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As soon as they entered the copse, Lady Catherine began in the following manner: You can be at no loss, Miss Carl, to understand the reason of my journey hither.",
    "entities": [
      [
        35,
        49,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        109,
        113,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "By Johnny, this attention was received with the greatest pleasure, but Allen still saw superciliousness in their treatment of everybody, hardly excepting even her sister, and could not like them; though their kindness to Johnny, such as it was, had a value as arising in all probability from the influence of their brothers admiration.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        71,
        76,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        221,
        227,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In vain did Hannah attempt to make her reasonable, and Leroy to make her resigned.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        18,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        55,
        60,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He addressed himself to Miss Anna, with a polite congratulation; Mr. Hurst also made her a slight bow, and said he was very glad; but diffuseness and warmth remained for Bingleys salutation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        69,
        74,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        170,
        178,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "but for you, dearest, loveliest Anna!",
    "entities": [
      [
        32,
        36,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Roy made no answer; and without attempting to persuade her ladyship to return into the house, walked quietly into it herself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        3,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mr. Wickham did not play at whist, and with ready delight was he received at the other table between Sally and Lydia.",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        11,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        101,
        106,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        111,
        116,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mrs. Mable was quite in the fidgets.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "That is all very proper and civil, I am sure, said Mrs. Marshall, and I dare say she is a very agreeable woman.",
    "entities": [
      [
        56,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Bruce joined them again only to say that her sister was worse, and that she could not leave her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "cried Emil, darting from her seat as she finished the letter, in eagerness to follow him, without losing a moment of the time so precious; but as she reached the door it was opened by a servant, and Mr. Bruce appeared.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        203,
        208,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Its effect was most extraordinary; for on first hearing it, Mrs. Flora sat quite still, and unable to utter a syllable.",
    "entities": [
      [
        42,
        47,
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        65,
        70,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It originated in Mrs. Isabelle, who, fatigued by the exercise of the morning, found Anthonys arm inadequate to her support, and consequently preferred her husbands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        65,
        76,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        84,
        92,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Rebecca was pleased; though when she asked herself the reason, she had very little to say in reply.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mack drew himself up with an effort and smiled.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]  
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Isn't it, Mr. Pete?",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Before which Jason?",
    "entities": [
      [
        14,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Your rank and wealth, Harry; my brains, such as they are my art, whatever it may be worth; Ella's good looks we shall all suffer for what the gods have given us, suffer terribly.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        27,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        91,
        95,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Never marry at all, Jessie.",
    "entities": [
      [
        21,
        27,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I am so glad I have found you, Leona,\" he said gravely.",
    "entities": [
      [
        32,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mildred drew a long breath.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]  
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "But here is Kimberly himself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        20,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lord Henry smiled and looked at Ethan. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        32,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Deny them, Lauren, deny them!",
    "entities": [
      [
        11,
        17,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"It is not much to ask of you, Eugene, and it is entirely for your own sake that I am speaking.",
    "entities": [
      [
        31,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"People like you the wilful sunbeams of life don't commit crimes, Nicholas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        66,
        74,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He felt that the eyes of Lonnie were fixed on him, and the consciousness that amongst his audience there was one whose temperament he wished to fascinate seemed to give his wit keenness and to lend colour to his imagination.",
    "entities": [
      [
        25,
        31,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"What nonsense, Jesse!\" laughed his companion, and as the hare bounded into the thicket, he fired.",
    "entities": [
      [
        16,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Jeffrey hurried along the quay through the drizzling rain.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Jeffrey's arms fell to his side.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I have no doubt it was not an accident, Elmer, though it must be put in that way to the public.",
    "entities": [
      [
        41,
        46,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I don't know that I shall tell you that, Mr. Phillip.",
    "entities": [
      [
        46,
        53,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I wish I could change places with you, Samuel.",
    "entities": [
      [
        39,
        45,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "And now good-bye, Florence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        18,
        26,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As soon as it was over, Stella rushed behind the scenes into the greenroom.",
    "entities": [
      [
        24,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Don't know who he is?\" said Jake, listlessly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Well, he seemed to think they were beyond his means,\" laughed Cecil.",
    "entities": [
      [
        63,
        68,
        "PERSON"
      ]  
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Olga,\" said Lord Henry, \"I had better tell them that the shooting is stopped for to-day.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        12,
        22,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "After two or three minutes of terrible silence, Allen turned round and came and stood behind him, putting his hand upon his shoulder.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        26,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        48,
        53,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Each of us has heaven and hell in him, Basil,\" cried Morris with a wild gesture of despair.",
    "entities": [
      [
        40,
        45,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        54,
        60,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "There is nothing that art cannot express, and I know that the work I have done, since I met William, is good work, is the best work of my life.",
    "entities": [
      [
        92,
        99,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Celia looked at him for a moment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I turned half-way round and saw Irma for the first time.",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        13,
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        32,
        36,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        45,
        50,
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I have heard all about it, Mr. Isabella,\" she answered.",
    "entities": [
      [
        32,
        40,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Lottie,\" she answered, lingering over his name with long-drawn music in her voice, as though it were sweeter than honey to the red petals of her mouth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        1,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "But suddenly people remarked that they scarcely spoke when they met and that Campbell seemed always to go away early from any party at which Thomas was present.",
    "entities": [
      [
        77,
        85,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        141,
        147,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"This is,\" interrupted Steven.",
    "entities": [
      [
        23,
        29,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I was very fond of Basil,\" said Willard with a note of sadness in his voice. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        20,
        25,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        33,
        40,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\" Roland shook his head.",
    "entities": [
      [
        1,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I am glad you appreciate my work at last, Willis,\" said the painter coldly when he had recovered from his surprise.",
    "entities": [
      [
        43,
        49,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He was an extremely clever young man, though he had no real appreciation of the visible arts, and whatever little sense of the beauty of poetry he possessed he had gained entirely from Lewis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        185,
        190,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"What o'clock is it, Steven?\" asked Rufus drowsily. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        21,
        27,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        36,
        41,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You have a wonderfully beautiful face, Mr. Ben.",
    "entities": [
      [
        43,
        46,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "By the way, Bonnie, you ran off very early last night.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        18,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        37,
        53,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "He opened it and found it was from Emmett.",
    "entities": [
      [
        35,
        41,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "my maid does that already, Mr. Alexis, when she is annoyed with me.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        31,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"You are not serious, Ann?\" she murmured.",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        25,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "A week later Nathan was sitting in the conservatory at Selby Royal, talking to the pretty Duchess of Monmouth, who with her husband, a jaded-looking man of sixty, was amongst his guests.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        12,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        13,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        55,
        66,
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        90,
        109,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It was so unlike Jean to speak like that.",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Aaron went back to his seat.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Because I have loved so many of them, Stephanie.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        39,
        48,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When Vincent had finished the letter, he felt that he had been forgiven.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "And now, Bertha, get up on the platform, and don't move about too much, or pay any attention to what Lord Henry says.",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        15,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        101,
        111,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The elaborate character of the frame had made the picture extremely bulky, and now and then, in spite of the obsequious protests of Mr. Hubbard, who had the true tradesman's spirited dislike of seeing a gentleman doing anything useful, Ina put his hand to it so as to help them.",
    "entities": [
      [
        136,
        143,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        236,
        239,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I wonder is that really so, Harry?\" said Eddie, putting some perfume on his handkerchief out of a large, gold-topped bottle that stood on the table.",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        34,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        42,
        47,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I am in Lady Agatha's black books at present,\" answered Johnnie with a funny look of penitence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        22,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        57,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In fact, it was music that had first brought him and Ruth together music and that indefinable attraction that Melvin seemed to be able to exercise whenever he wished and, indeed, exercised often without being conscious of it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        53,
        57,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        110,
        116,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Don't keep Jesse too long.",
    "entities": [
      [
        11,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"To see my soul!\" muttered Madison, starting up from the sofa and turning almost white from fear. \"Yes,\" answered Winifred gravely, and with deep-toned sorrow in his voice, \"to see your soul.",
    "entities": [
      [
        27,
        34,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        114,
        122,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"She is quite beautiful, Nicholas,\" he said, \"but she can't act.",
    "entities": [
      [
        25,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"With their ages, Lady Marguerite?\" asked Alvin.",
    "entities": [
      [
        18,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        42,
        47,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\" exclaimed Opal, a strange sense of terror creeping over him.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"But, my dear Lizzie \" \"Yes, Harry, I know what you are going to say.",
    "entities": [
      [
        14,
        20,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        29,
        34,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lester put the letter into his pocket.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Jennifer shook his head, as he entered, and followed Joseph into the library.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        53,
        59,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Irving is engaged to be married,\" said Lord David, watching him as he spoke.",
    "entities": [
      [
        1,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        40,
        50,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Thelma glanced at the picture, and suddenly an uncontrollable feeling of hatred for Frank Hallward came over him, as though it had been suggested to him by the image on the canvas, whispered into his ear by those grinning lips.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        84,
        98,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Jack is far too wise not to do foolish things now",
    "entities": [
      [
        1,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Ashley, if I told you, you might like me less than you do, and you would certainly laugh at me.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"All right, Jean.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As they entered the studio, Patrick put his hand upon Lord Peter's arm.",
    "entities": [
      [
        28,
        35,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        59,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Frank shook his head, and a look of annoyance passed over his face at the mention of the word \"inquest.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"You really must not say things like that before Floyd, Harry.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        49,
        54,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        56,
        61,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mr. Rachel?",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Nannie shook his head.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"By the way, Luther,\" he said after a pause, \"'what does it profit a man if he gain the whole world and lose how does the quotation run?",
    "entities": [
      [
        13,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "But you, Keith, with your pure, bright, innocent face, and your marvellous untroubled youth I can't believe anything against you.",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You have annoyed Dennis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        23,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Play me a nocturne, Willie, and, as you play, tell me, in a low voice, how you have kept your youth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        20,
        26,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Josephine, you mustn't let this thing get on your nerves.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ]  
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\" Ina shrugged his shoulders.",
    "entities": [
      [
        2,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"You can dine with me to-night, Andrew, can't you?\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        22,
        30,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        32,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"With an actress,\" said Myrtle, blushing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        24,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Years ago, when I was a boy,\" said Douglas, crushing the flower in his hand, \"you met me, flattered me, and taught me to be vain of my good looks.",
    "entities": [
      [
        1,
        10,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        36,
        43,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Where I heard the name of Lewis.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        27,
        32,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As the door closed, Virginia put the key in his pocket and looked round the room.",
    "entities": [
      [
        20,
        28,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Logan, if it would please you.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You, Mr. Paul, you yourself, with your rose-red youth and your rose-white boyhood, you have had passions that have made you afraid, thoughts that have filled you with terror, day-dreams and sleeping dreams whose mere memory might stain your cheek with shame \" \"Stop!\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        13,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"No, of course not,\" cried Laura. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        27,
        32,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "If Theresa's life were spoiled, no one would be sorrier than yourself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I don't feel up to it,\" said Sadie listlessly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        30,
        35,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I shall stay with the real Arthur,\" he said, sadly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        28,
        34,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Don't go to the theatre to-night, Harriet,\" said Danielle.",
    "entities": [
      [
        35,
        42,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        50,
        58,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "In less than a quarter of an hour, Lizzie was galloping down the long avenue as hard as he could go.",
    "entities": [
      [
        3,
        33,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        35,
        41,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Women who had wildly adored him, and for his sake had braved all social censure and set convention at defiance, were seen to grow pallid with shame or horror if Abraham entered the room.",
    "entities": [
      [
        161,
        168,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Rose, from the moment I met you, your personality had the most extraordinary influence over me.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "What had Bobby to do with Sibyl Vane's death?",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        14,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        26,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Rebecca is my dearest friend,\" he said.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As they entered they saw Nell.",
    "entities": [
      [
        25,
        29,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You must not be angry with me, Roosevelt, for what I have told you.",
    "entities": [
      [
        31,
        40,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Wesley says she is beautiful, and he is not often wrong about things of that kind.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Effie started.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "So sorry I am late, Alex.",
    "entities": [
      [
        20,
        24,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When they reached the top landing, Michelle took out the key and turned it in the lock.",
    "entities": [
      [
        35,
        43,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I forget,\" said Debra.",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        22,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Don't speak about those days, Kathryn they are dead.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        13,
        29,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        31,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Ira's whims are laws to everybody, except himself.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]  
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Eunice had not killed her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It is not in you, Alton, to commit a murder.",
    "entities": [
      [
        18,
        23,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "The same look of pity came into Pete's eyes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        32,
        36,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "My dear Clyde,\" answered Lord David, \"you merely fainted.",
    "entities": [
      [
        8,
        13,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        30,
        35,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I shall be here at eleven,\" said Elmer.",
    "entities": [
      [
        19,
        25,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        33,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Come, Mr. Isabella, my hansom is outside, and I can drop you at your own place.",
    "entities": [
      [
        11,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\" Vincent did not answer for a few moments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        2,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        29,
        42,
        "TIME"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As the chime struck one, Campbell turned round, and looking at Verna, saw that his eyes were filled with tears.",
    "entities": [
      [
        25,
        33,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        63,
        68,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"You will have tea, of course, Perry?",
    "entities": [
      [
        31,
        36,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"A very charming artistic basis for ethics, Kathryn!",
    "entities": [
      [
        44,
        51,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\" Jennifer frowned and turned his head away.",
    "entities": [
      [
        2,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lloyd sighed and lit a cigarette.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Ah, Alan,\" murmured Frederick with a sigh, \"I wish you had a thousandth part of the pity for me that I have for you.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        21,
        30,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I wish it were fin du globe,\" said Gloria with a sigh.",
    "entities": [
      [
        36,
        42,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Her white hands were moving daintily among the cups, and her full red lips were smiling at something that Wilbur had whispered to her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        106,
        112,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Besides, what on earth could happen to you, Curtis?",
    "entities": [
      [
        44,
        50,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I wish I could love,\" cried Catherine with a deep note of pathos in his voice. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        29,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Certainly with hideous iteration the bitten lips of Will shaped and reshaped those subtle words that dealt with soul and sense, till he had found in them the full expression, as it were, of his mood, and justified, by intellectual approval,",
    "entities": [
      [
        53,
        56,
        "PERSON"
      ]  
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Good-bye, Mr. Russell.",
    "entities": [
      [
        14,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Jacqueline,\" said Lord Henry at last, as the chaud-froid was being handed round,",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        18,
        28,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It was clear to him that the experimental method was the only method by which one could arrive at any scientific analysis of the passions; and certainly Adam was a subject made to his hand, and seemed to promise rich and fruitful results.",
    "entities": [
      [
        153,
        157,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Don't pay any attention to him, Irma,\" said the painter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        33,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Miriam turned slowly around and looked at him with tear-dimmed eyes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        6,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "No,\" said Everett, \"there is nothing fearful about it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        10,
        17,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "There was something about Thomas that charmed everybody.",
    "entities": [
      [
        26,
        32,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Carl?",
    "entities": [
      [
        1,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"You will write to me if you want anything, won't you?\" said Emily, after a pause.",
    "entities": [
      [
        61,
        66,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lord Henry went out to the garden and found Bryan burying his face in the great cool lilac-blossoms, feverishly drinking in their perfume as if it had been wine.",
    "entities": [
      [
        5,
        10,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        44,
        49,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I hope not,\" said Isabel with a sad look in his eyes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        19,
        25,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"You are too charming to go in for philanthropy, Mr. Juanita far too charming.",
    "entities": [
      [
        53,
        60,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "But won't you miss your train?\" said Glenn languidly as he passed up the steps and opened the door with his latch-key.",
    "entities": [
      [
        37,
        42,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Safe from what, Fred?",
    "entities": [
      [
        17,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Dear Lady Narborough,\" murmured Wesley, smiling, \"I have not been in love for a whole week not, in fact, since Madame de Ferrol left town.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        33,
        39,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        112,
        128,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lying back in the hansom, with his hat pulled over his forehead, Roy watched with listless eyes the sordid shame of the great city, and now",
    "entities": [
      [
        65,
        68,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"I know what pleasure is,\" cried Gloria.",
    "entities": [
      [
        33,
        39,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "It was the creation of such worlds as these that seemed to Jack to be the true object, or amongst the true objects, of life; and in his search for sensations that would be at once new and delightful, and possess that element of strangeness that is so essential to romance, he would often adopt certain modes of thought that he knew to be really alien to his nature, abandon himself to their subtle influences, and then, having, as it were, caught their colour and satisfied his intellectual curiosity, leave them with that curious indifference that is not incompatible with a real ardour of temperament, and that, indeed, according to certain modern psychologists, is often a condition of it.",
    "entities": [
      [
        59,
        63,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Roy drew a long breath.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        3,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Men who talked grossly became silent when Morris entered the room.",
    "entities": [
      [
        42,
        48,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Edwin lifted his golden head from the pillow, and with pallid face and tear-stained eyes, looked at him as he walked over to the deal painting-table that was set beneath the high curtained window.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I have sorrows, Amy, of my own, that even you know nothing of.",
    "entities": [
      [
        16,
        19,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\" Peter shook his head.",
    "entities": [
      [
        2,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"What do you say to that, Mr. Sylvester?\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        30,
        39,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Well, Claude,\" he said at length, with a sad smile, \"I won't speak to you again about this horrible thing, after to-day.",
    "entities": [
      [
        6,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Mark smiled.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        4,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "As the glass door closed behind Ralph, Lord Henry turned and looked at the duchess with his slumberous eyes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        32,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        44,
        49,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Do you think my nature so shallow?\" cried Ora angrily. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        43,
        46,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Why have you stopped playing, Jessie?",
    "entities": [
      [
        31,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"It is the real Judith that is all.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        16,
        22,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "4 One afternoon, a month later, Lizzie was reclining in a luxurious arm-chair, in the little library of Lord Henry's house in Mayfair.",
    "entities": [
      [
        2,
        15,
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        17,
        30,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        32,
        38,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        109,
        114,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        126,
        133,
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Not very good, Martha.",
    "entities": [
      [
        15,
        21,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lillian shook his head. \"",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Motionless, and as one in a dream, sat Gordon, gazing at her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        39,
        45,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"It should matter everything to you, Mr. Elizabeth.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        41,
        50,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Virginia took the note up and read it carefully.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "What you have to do is this \" \"Stop, Thelma.",
    "entities": [
      [
        37,
        43,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I have asked myself and Mr. Cornelius.",
    "entities": [
      [
        28,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Isabelle heaved a sigh of relief as he saw the gardener approaching.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Beverly listened, open-eyed and wondering.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "When the sound of their footsteps had died away, Leslie locked the door and put the key in his pocket.",
    "entities": [
      [
        49,
        55,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"Life has everything in store for you, Carrie.",
    "entities": [
      [
        39,
        45,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You have never been to any of my parties, have you, Mr. Kimberly?",
    "entities": [
      [
        56,
        64,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Roosevelt loathed him more than ever.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Loretta heaved a sigh, and Lord Henry strolled across the room and began to stroke the head of a curious Java parrot, a large, grey-plumaged bird with pink crest and tail, that was balancing itself upon a bamboo perch.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        32,
        37,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        105,
        109,
        "NORP"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"How long Mr. Pamela is!\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        14,
        20,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I tell you, Ollie, that it is on things like these that our lives depend.",
    "entities": [
      [
        12,
        17,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "it was Edgar's own face that he was looking at!",
    "entities": [
      [
        7,
        12,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "\"It is only the sacred things that are worth touching, Irene,\" said Lord Henry, with a strange touch of pathos in his voice.",
    "entities": [
      [
        55,
        60,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        68,
        78,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Glenn half opened the door.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        6,
        10,
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "For years, Megan could not free himself from the influence of this book.",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        9,
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        11,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I cannot forget that,\" said Kenneth simply.",
    "entities": [
      [
        28,
        35,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I don't want to see Bruce tied to some vile creature, who might degrade his nature and ruin his intellect.\"",
    "entities": [
      [
        20,
        25,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Frank said nothing, but rose from the table, and passing into the next room, sat down to the piano and let his fingers stray across the white and black ivory of the keys.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Diane was sleeping quite peacefully, lying on his right side, with one hand underneath his cheek.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        5,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "You have saved my life,\" said Jordan.",
    "entities": [
      [
        30,
        36,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "said with musical utterance, that Mable's soul had turned to this white girl and bowed in worship before her.",
    "entities": [
      [
        34,
        39,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Not that Matthew complained, to be sure; he listened to it all with a wordless smile of enjoyment on his face; Marilla permitted the chatter until she found herself becoming too interested in it, whereupon she always promptly quenched Amelia by a curt command to hold her tongue.",
    "entities": [
      [
        9,
        16,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        111,
        118,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        235,
        241,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "I was awfully near giving up in despair, explained Lee.",
    "entities": [
      [
        51,
        54,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "She was secretly vastly pleased at Jacobs impulsive caress, which was probably the reason why she said brusquely:",
    "entities": [
      [
        35,
        41,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Marilla lifted her worn face from her hands and looked at Oscar.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        7,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        58,
        63,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Oh, Diana, whispered Jerome, finding it necessary to lean up against a maple tree for support",
    "entities": [
      [
        4,
        9,
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        21,
        27,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Lawrence had gathered them and brought them to him, her anguished, tearless eyes burning in her white face.",
    "entities": [
      [
        0,
        8,
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "content": "Somehow Susan who did not notice the rather guilty little start of surprise the white-lace girl gave, and would not have understood the subtle compliment implied therein if she had got on her feet, and moved dizzily out to the front.",
